客户服务  有什么可以帮你的吗
Customer service. May I help you?
我在  阿兰·马斯特斯
Yes. I'm here. Alan Masters.
账户34697721
It's account number 34697721.
你们最近增加了探险频道
You guys recently added the Adventure Channel,
我也付了费
and I paid to get it,
-但我的屏幕是花的  -不是我们部门的事
- but my screen is all wavy, so - Wrong department, sir.
什么意思
No, what do you mean, wrong department?
-我按的3  -请稍后
- I pressed 3. - Please hold.
别让等  我都等了45分钟了
Don't you put me on hold. I've been on hold for 45 min--
你的来电对我们非常重要
Your call is very important to us.
-请继续等待  -喂喂
- Please continue holding. - Hello, hello, hello, hello!
非常抱歉  先生
Sorry about that, sir.
我可以把你接给正确的部门了
I can connect you to the correct department now.
先生
Sir?
你没事吧  喂
Are you okay? Hello?
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
看你睡觉
Watching you sleep.
恐不恐怖
Is that creepy?
我觉得很温馨
I think it's sweet.
我还照了相
I took some pictures.
不那么温馨了
Less sweet.
是一系列的  你一般不会醒来的
They're part of a series. Usually you don't wake up.
这下恐怖了
And now it's creepy.
我在想
I've been thinking...
不
Oh, no.
放心  我已经放弃零重力做爱的事了
Oh, relax. I'm over that whole sex-in-zero-g thing.
很好  那是绝对要出意外的
Good, 'cause that was just an accident waiting to happen.
但说真的
Seriously, though.
我觉得我们该改变一下了
I think it's time we shake things up.
搬去巴黎
Move to Paris, you know,
去尼泊尔寻找埋藏宝藏
search for buried treasure in Nepal.
我们可以乘热气球穿过撒哈拉
We could fly a hot air balloon across the Sahara.
知道吗  我喜欢那些点子
You know what? I love all of those ideas,
但我才刚当上警监
but I just became captain,
你还要经营你的私家侦探生意
and you have your P.I. business.
还要洛克塞特
And then there's LokSat.
是啊
Exactly.
我们有责任  是吧
We have responsibilities, right?
如果我们没有呢
But what if we didn't?
请稍后
Hold, please.
我可能得接  或许是有命案呢
Um, I might need that. That might be a homicide.
被害人不会死得更透了
The victim's not gonna get any deader.
听我说
Listen.
如果我们找到了洛克塞特  拿下了他
Let's say we find LokSat and take him down --
而且不被反杀
without getting killed.
然后呢
What then?
你不会当很久的12分局警监
You're not gonna be captain of the 12th Precinct for very long.
你平步青云  不可阻挡
You're on a rocket. Sky's the limit.
你知道到时会怎么样吗
So you know what happens then?
我们成为普通人
We become normal.
不  卡塞尔  你永远不会成为普通人
No, Castle, you're never gonna be normal.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
-想想吧  -我会的
- Think about it. - I will.
什么情况
What do you got?
阿兰·马斯特斯
Alan Masters.
一切迹象表明是中毒
All signs point to poison --
瞳孔放大  唇色发青
dilated pupils, bluish discoloration around the lips.
这是明显征兆
That's a giveaway,
但得等尸检完毕才能确定
but I'll know for sure after the autopsy.
谁报的警
Who called it in?
他有线电视公司的客服接线员
Customer-service operator for his cable company.
事发时她正在跟他打电话
She was on the phone with him when it happened.
好个死法
What a way to go.
毒死还是跟有线电视公司打电话
Poisoned or on the phone with the cable company?
至少毒发很快
Well, at least the poison was quick.
看来凶手把窗户撬开了
Looks like our killer jimmied that window open.
邻居认为昨晚8点左右听到了
Neighbor thought she heard somebody on the fire escape
有人走防火梯
last night around 8:00.
他怎么中毒的
How was he poisoned?
饮水
In his water.
厨房水槽下面的滤水器
The filter underneath the kitchen sink
被动了手脚
was tampered with.
讽刺的是  他是城市安全检查员
Ironically, he works for the city as a safety inspector.
如果我是个人物性格专家  而我就是
You know, if I were an expert on character, which I am,
我会说阿兰算是个梦想家
I would say that Alan was a bit of a dreamer,
白天在街头进行调查
spending his days on the ground inspecting things
但晚上  却做起梦来
but his nights in the clouds,
幻想着冒险
fantasizing of adventure.
不幸的是  他还没真正体验生活
Tragically, his life was cut short
就早逝了
before he ever truly lived.
怎么回事
What's going on?
或许没有
Or not.
你们都在我公寓里做什么
What are you all doing in my apartment?
蕾妮
Um, Lanie.
别看我  他刚刚明明死了
Don't "Um, Lanie" me. That man was dead!
他现在可活得好好的
Well, he's very much alive now.
他当时没有脉搏  没有呼吸声
He had no pulse, no breath sounds,
而且瞳孔放大固定
and his pupils were dilated and fixed.
那尸僵  尸斑呢
Was there rigor mortis, lividity?
没有  但他当时死了还不到一小时
No, but he'd been dead less than an hour.
蕾妮  被害人真的...
Lanie, hey. Is it true that our victim was --
他都死了  我会做工作的
He was dead, okay? I know how to do my job.
好嘛  冷静  没事的  我就...
Okay, calm down. It's all good. I just --
不不  不是没事
No, no, no. It's not all good.
我差点往他肝脏里插了根温度计
I almost stuck a thermometer in his liver.
他情况稳定了吗
Uh, so is he stable?
我还在做测试
Well, I'm still running tests,
但他似乎非常健康
but he seems completely healthy
尽管他摄入了足以致死的河豚毒素
despite having ingested a deadly dose of tetrodotoxin.
河豚毒素
TTX.
是一种很多鱼类含有的毒素
It's a neurotoxin found in several species of fish.
效力很强
It's extremely potent.
但他还是活了下来  有什么解释吗
And yet he survived, so do you have an explanation.
不  但你丈夫有
No, but your husband sure does.
你就是当代拉撒路
You are a modern-day Lazarus,
你起死回生  好回答那个永恒的问题
risen from the grave to answer the eternal question --
另一边什么样
What's on the other side?
对不起  你是谁来着
I'm sorry. Who are you again?
请原谅他  马斯特斯先生
You'll have to forgive him, Mr. Masters.
他很容易激动
He's very excitable.
抱歉  我觉得揭秘
Well, excuse me if I find pulling back the curtain
我们死后会发生什么实在有点令人激动
on what happens when we die just a tad exciting.
是有白光吗  还是类似隧道那种
Was there a white light or is it more of a tunnel thing?
我记得的最后一件事
The last thing I remember,
是服药  想把有线电视修好
I was taking my pills, trying to get my cable fixed,
然后我就醒来了  公寓里全是警察
and then I woke up - to an apartment full of police.
没有灵魂出窍体验吗
So, no out-of-body experience?
你有什么仇家吗
Do you have any enemies?
我  没有  我就是个普通人
Me? No. I'm an average guy.
我上班  我回家
I go to work, I come home.
但你有更广大的梦想  是吧
But you dream of so much more, don't you?
你怎么知道的
How do you know that?
你读了我的日记吗
Did you read my diary?
没有  我看到了你的照片...
No, I saw your pictures on your --
你还记日记吗
Wait, you keep a diary?
作为大老爷们  管那叫日志比较好
As a grown man, call it a journal.
工作上呢
What about work?
你最近有惹怒什么公司同事吗
Have you upset anyone there recently?
有
Yeah.
有个我手下的人
There is this guy that works for me --
之前是我的手下  戴夫·巴顿
well, used to work for me -- Dave Barton.
我不得不解雇了他  因为他
I had to fire him because he was letting
对严重的违规只给予了警告处理
serious infractions slide with just a warning.
是因为受贿吗
Was it for money?
据传是如此
That was the rumor.
他解雇他时  他的确显得有些生气
And he did seem a little miffed when I let him go.
我把他留给我的语音信息放给你们听
I'll play you the message that he left me.
你个臭蛆
You slimy little maggot.
我要用生锈的勺子捅你
I'm gonna stab you with a rusty spoon
用你的肠子勒死你
and strangle you with your own intestines.
要不
Or better yet,
我要逼你一个个吃下你的脚趾
I'm gonna force-feed you your toes one by one,
然后再把你烧了
and then I'm gonna light you on fire.
首先  我要用羊角锤把你打瘫
First, I'm gonna paralyze you with a claw hammer
然后往你身上倒一堆蚂蚁  你个混蛋
and then cover you with ants, you son of a bitch!
之后还有一堆
And it goes on and on like that for a while.
你就没想着该报警吗
And you never thought to call the police?
告戴夫吗  不
On Dave? No!
他就是神经比较大条
He's just got a big personality.
没办法  我有愤怒问题
What can I say? I have anger issues.
以及杀人创意天赋
And a gift for murderous creativity.
威胁要"把阿兰的脚钉在天花板上
Threatening to "Nail Alan to the ceiling by his feet
用大球棒把他的脸当彩罐打开花"
and pinata the hell out of his face with a Fungo bat."
就是狠话而已
It's all just talk.
我其实是晕血的
I actually get nauseous at the sight of blood.
所以你决定昨晚给阿兰下毒吗
Oh, is that why you decided to poison Alan last night?
我昨晚在家
Hey, I was home last night
跟我妻子和岳母在一起
with my wife and my mother-in-law,
相信我  那对我的愤怒问题毫无帮助
which, believe you me, is no good for my anger issues.
那女人简直能逼疯我
I mean, that woman drives me crazy.
有时候我真想拿个搅拌机
Sometimes I just think about getting a blender
和泥铲
and a trowel and --
开玩笑的
Kidding.
你最好希望你的不在场证明能核实
Well, you better hope your alibi holds up,
你有充足的动机
'cause you had all the motive in the world.
你要动机
You want motive?
我们是安全检查员
We're safety inspectors.
你以为我们开出
You think we're making friends
数百万的罚单能交朋友吗
handing out millions in fines?
我们可收不到圣诞贺卡
We're not getting any Christmas cards.
尤其是阿兰
Especially Alan.
什么意思
What do you mean, especially Alan?
大家都知道他这人一丝不苟
The guy's got a rep for being a real stickler.
他不放过任何东西
He doesn't let anything slide.
你就是这样吗
Oh, is that what you did --
为点小钱就放人一马
let things slide in exchange for a payday?
或许吧  或许没有
Maybe I did, maybe I didn't.
那我也不是杀人犯
Doesn't make me a killer.
重点是  阿兰不肯通融
The point is that Alan refuses to play the game.
这让很多人生气
And that pisses off a lot of people.
蕾妮真的宣布了一个活人死亡吗
Did Lanie really declare a live guy dead?
没有  好吧  是的
No. Well, yeah,
但就算帮你自己个忙  别跟她提
but do yourself a favor -- Don't mention it to her.
有发现吗
So, you got something?
我在洛克塞特方面可能有突破发现
I might have broken open LokSat.
你找到他们了
You found them?
很不幸  没有  但我找到了另一个人
Unfortunately, no, but I did find someone else.
依据卡塞尔发现的洛克塞特飞到
Based on Castle's discovery of the exact time and date
洛杉矶的准确日期时间
LokSat flew into L.A.,
我一直在看所有
I've been scrubbing footage
洛杉矶附近机场的视频
from all the Los Angeles area airports.
看这是谁
Look who showed up.
卡莱布·布朗
Caleb Brown?
但他是用的假名出行  彼得·麦克加菲
But he was traveling under an alias -- Peter McCaffery.
卡莱布肯定是去洛杉矶跟洛克塞特见面了
So, Caleb must have gone to L.A. To meet with LokSat.
但开SUV的是谁
But who's driving the S.U.V.?
我不知道  我只能看到部分车牌
I don't know. I can only read part of the plate,
但我在列出可能匹配的清单
but I'm generating a list of possible matches.
警监
Captain.
戴夫·巴顿的不在场证明核实了
Dave Barton alibied out,
但我们在列出阿兰最近
but we're getting a list of all the companies
罚了款或停了业的店家名单
that Alan has either fined or shut down for violations recently.
然后我们会让阿兰看一遍清单
Then we're gonna run the list past Alan.
他的未遂杀人犯还逍遥在外
Whose would-be killer is still out there,
你采取了什么防范措施
so what precautions are you taking?
警车把他从医院接回家了
Squad car just brought him home from the hospital.
我们派了警员在他门外站岗
We got a uniform posted outside his door,
所以他唯一真正的担忧  是你丈夫
which makes his only real concern your husband.
嗯
Yeah.
你死而重生了
So, you have died and been reborn.
你现在打算怎么办
What are you gonna do now?
上床睡觉
Going to bed.
我明天还有一整天的检查要做呢
I have a full day of inspections tomorrow.
我得精神振奋
I need to be focused.
你不能装作什么都没发生似的回去工作
You can't just go back to work like nothing happened.
这是一次频死经历  是一记警钟啊
You had a near-death experience. That's a wake-up call.
走入世界
Get out there.
过上你一直梦想的生活吧
Live this life you've always dreamed about.
我墙上虽然挂了些照片
Just because I have a few pictures on my wall
不代表我对生活有什么不满
doesn't mean I'm not happy with my life.
是啊  你枯燥孤独的生活
Right. Your drab, solitary life.
才不孤独呢
It's not solitary.
那么有位安全检查员太太吗
So there's a Ms. Safety Inspector?
没有
Not exactly.
但我有个心仪的女人
But there is a woman I have my eye on.
她幽默  聪明
She's funny and smart.
-但不知道你的存在  -不知道
- Doesn't know you exist? - No.
安全
All clear.
如果你需要什么  我就在门外
I'll be right outside if you need anything.
很好  谢谢
Great, thanks.
你该打给这个女人
You should really call this woman.
好  我会的
Okay, I will.
你真不记得死亡的任何事了吗
And you honestly don't remember anything about being dead?
真心不
Really don't.
谁会那样啊  谁会那样得到第二次机会
Who does that? Who gets a second chance like that
然后第二天还起来去上班
and just goes to work the next morning?
我会的  我喜欢工作
I would. I like work.
阿兰
Alan!
有人在床上动了手脚  想电死他
Someone rigged the bed to electrocute him.
他死了吗
Is he dead?
抱歉  卡塞尔  他这次真的死了
Sorry, Castle, but this time, he really is dead.
真是可惜
What a waste.
得到了第二次机会
To be given a second chance
然后又这样被夺走
and have it taken away like this.
他原打算像没事人一样回去工作
He was just gonna go back to work like nothing happened.
什么
What?
如果我不是那么专注于他的重生
If I hadn't been so focused on his rebirth,
本可能会注意到电线的
I might have noticed that wire.
我本可以救他的
I could have saved him.
别自责  卡塞尔
You can't beat yourself up, Castle.
我还以为他是个医学奇迹呢
I was starting to think he was some kind of medical miracle.
原来他之前只是走运
Turns out, he was just lucky.
最终  他的运气也用光了
And in the end, his luck ran out.
什么运气啊
Forget lucky.
有人烤肉了吗
Somebody cooking barbecue?
他有不死之身
He's immortal.
-他之前绝对死了  -你上次就那么说的
- He was definitely dead. - That's what you said last time.
他上次也死了
He was dead the last time, too.
抱歉
Uh, sorry.
能让我们说一句吗
Um, can we have a minute, please?
-当然  -谢谢
- Of course. - Thanks.
抱歉  我好凌乱
I'm sorry. I'm just rattled.
人是可能中毒或触电
You know, people can come back from being poisoned
而不死  但一天两次
and from being electrocuted, but both in the same day?
有什么解释吗
So, is there an explanation?
我能想到两个
I can think of two.
要么我是工作能力不行
Either I'm really bad at my job
要么卡塞尔是对的  这人有不死之身
or Castle's right and this guy is immortal.
他不是不死之身
He is not immortal,
你在工作上是个天才
and you are a genius at your job.
我们得继续寻找答案
We just got to keep looking for answers,
首先就是谁那么想杀了他
starting with who wants to kill this guy so badly.
第二次刺杀企图有什么鉴证证据吗
Is there any forensics on the second attempt?
没有  床肯定是
No. The bed must have been wired
结束了犯罪现场证据搜集后
after the apartment was already released
才布上了线
from being a crime scene,
所以凶手在阿兰和卡塞尔回去之前
which means the killer had about a two-hour window
有两小时的时机
before Alan and Castle got there.
本该杀死阿兰的毒素  河豚毒素
So, the toxin that should have killed Alan, TTX,
是一种管制药物
is a controlled substance,
只有少数制药公司有
available through only a few pharma supply companies.
疾控中心正要发名单给我们
CDC is sending us over a list right.
那么找到买家或许就能找到凶手
So, finding the buyer might lead to the killer.
知道阿兰为什么还没死吗
Any idea how our boy Alan is still with us?
不知道  但卡塞尔有个理论
Uh, no. But Castle has a theory.
你是个超级英雄
You are a superhero.
我真不是  我就是个普通人
No, I'm really not. I'm just an ordinary guy.
你本来是个普通人  阿兰
You were an ordinary guy, Alan.
大部分超级英雄起初就是这样
That's how most superheroes start out --
温和弱小的人  这就是你
mild-mannered weaklings, and that's you!
多谢夸奖
Wow, thanks.
放心  这都是为了突出你的转化
Relax. It's all to maximize your transformative arc.
如果我认同你的看法  你能让我一个人静静吗
If I agree with you, will you leave me alone?
别傻了  我们这才开始
Don't be silly. We're just getting started!
首先  我们得想明白
First, we need to figure out
是什么触发了你的转化
what triggered your transformation,
可以说是你的起源故事
your origin story, if you will.
为什么
Why?
因为起源故事就是一切
Because the origin story is everything!
关于这个有九部蜘蛛侠故事吧
What, there's, what, nine Spider-Man movies about it?
喂
Yo.
有线索了
We got a lead.
我们得给阿兰想个超级英雄名字
We need to come up with a superhero name for Alan.
不不  不需要
No. No, we really don't.
安全侠怎么样
How about... Safety Man?
烂透了
No, that's terrible.
他有其他超能力吗
Well, does he have any other powers?
不知道  我们该检测一下
I don't know. We should really run some tests.
你刚提到了线索
Um, you said something about a lead...
是啊  我们查了一下你的检查历史
Right. Yeah, we've been checking into your inspection history
看你是否惹怒了什么人
to see if there's somebody you might have pissed off.
可能找到了  赞提姆实验室
I think we have a winner -- Zantium Labs.
你刚给他们开了六位数的罚单
You just hit them with a six-figure fine.
是啊  他们是一家生物制药公司
Yeah, they're a biopharmaceutical company.
他们两天前发生了
I threatened to shut them down
严重化学品泄漏事故  我威胁要关停他们
after they had a bad chemical spill two days ago.
化学品泄漏事故
A chemical spill?
谜题解决了
Mystery solved.
接触危险物质是最常见的
Exposure to dangerous materials is the most common
超级英雄起源故事
superhero origin story there is.
抱歉  泄漏的是LAH
Sorry. The spill was L.A.H.
是一种无机化合物  是作为催化剂
It's an inorganic compound used as a catalyst
制作其他化合物的
to make other chemicals, which --
重点是  这东西有爆炸性
The point is, it can be explosive,
但是绝不会把人变成
but there's nothing about it that would ever turn anyone
该怎么说呢
into a, I don't know...
酷毙队长
Captain Cool?
不  继续想
No. But keep trying.
这次泄漏的责任人是谁
Hey, who's on the hook for that spill?
实验室经理  弗兰克·帕切特
The lab manager, Frank Patchett.
他求我不要开罚单的
He begged me not to fine him.
他说实验室在大量流失资金
He said the lab was hemorrhaging money.
听上去像动机
That sounds like motive.
走吧  卡塞尔  我们去跟他谈谈
Come on, Castle. Let's go talk to this guy.
等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
或许我该一起去
Maybe I should come with you.
为什么
Why?
不为什么
No reason.
那姑娘
The girl.
就是还不知道你存在的那个
The one who doesn't know you exist.
她在那儿工作  是吧
She works there, doesn't she?
不是  是
No. Yes.
她叫格温  营销部的
Her name is Gwen. She's in marketing.
抱歉  阿兰  你得待在这里
Sorry, Alan. You got to stay here.
如果赞提姆实验室有人想杀你
If there's someone at Zantium Labs trying to kill you,
而我还带你去那儿  那我就是最差劲的警察了
I'd be the worst cop on the force if I took you there.
别担心  阿兰
Don't worry, Alan.
我会替你在格温面前美言几句的
I'll put in a good for you with Gwen!
不要  别啊
No, no! Please -- Please don't!
真不敢相信会有人那么害可怜的阿兰
I can't believe someone would try and do that to poor Alan.
他人那么好
He's such a sweet man.
-你认识他啊  -当然
- So you do know him? - Of course.
这里的人挺恨他的
People around here kind of hate him,
但  怎么说呢  我觉得他挺逗的
but, I don't know, I think he's really funny.
我会转告的
Oh, I'll tell him you said that.
那就是弗兰克  弗兰克
Oh, that's Frank. Hey, Frank.
谢谢
Thank you.
帕切特先生  我是埃斯波西托警探
Mr. Patchett. I'm Detective Esposito.
我要问你几个关于阿兰·马斯特斯的问题
I need to ask you a few questions about Alan Masters.
他还好吧
Is he doing okay?
我听说有人企图杀他
I heard someone tried to kill him.
两次呢
Twice.
清理工作如何了
How's the cleanup going?
就快完成了
Oh, well, we're almost done here.
意外常有  幸好没人受伤
Accidents happen. Luckily, nobody was hurt.
除了阿兰
Nobody except Alan.
你觉得他的遭遇跟泄漏事故有关吗
You think what happened to him is connected to the spill?
或许吧
Maybe.
你换身衣服  我们好好谈谈
So why don't you get changed, and we can go talk about it.
好  换衣室在那边
Okay. Locker room's over there.
我们一起去
We'll go with you.
其实  我想到处去看看
Actually, I'm gonna go take a look around.
起源故事
Origin story.
-打扰  -嗯
- Excuse me. - Yes.
我能帮你什么吗
Can I help you with something?
是的  你真能  麦克
Yes, as a matter of fact, you can, uh, Mike.
如果你要在这个实验室里选一样
Look, um, if you had to pick something in this lab
能把人变成超级英雄的东西
that would turn somebody into a superhero,
你会选什么
what would it be?
抱歉  什么
I'm -- I'm sorry. What?
放射性蜘蛛  秘密外星科技
Radioactive spider, secret alien technology,
超级士兵血清
super-soldier serum --
嗯  我们这儿没有那种东西
Yeah, we don't have anything like that here.
那这个呢
Then what is -- What about this?
你们这儿忙什么呢
What are you working on right here?
我们发现了刺激老鼠
We've discovered an accelerated method
发细胞加速生长的办法
for growing hair cells in the mice.
加速细胞再生
Accelerated cell regeneration?
这或许是通往永生的关键
That could be the key to immortality.
我这48小时里一直在
I've been supervising this cleanup
监督清理的事
for the last 48 hours.
就算我想杀阿兰
Even if I wanted to kill Alan,
我也没有时机或精力
I didn't have the opportunity or the energy.
但你有动机
But you did have the motive.
你求他不要开罚单  但他还是开了
You begged him not to fine you, and he did anyway.
是啊
Yeah.
他很烦人  但损害已经造成了
He's a pain in the ass, but the damage was already done.
杀了他也不会得到什么
Killing him would have accomplished nothing.
我送他去停车场时
You know, something odd did happen
的确发生了怪事
when I walked him out to the parking lot.
什么怪事
Odd how?
有人当时在阿兰的车附近
There was someone hanging out at Alan's car,
但看到我们走来就走开了
but he took off when he saw us coming.
我当时没怎么细想  但是
I didn't think much of it at the time, but...
你们停车场有监控吗
Does your parking lot have security cameras?
-有  -我看看
- Yeah. - Let me see him.
休姆先生  你是最近被阿兰关停的一家
Mr. Hume, so you're an operations manager at a plastics factory
塑料厂的营运经理
that Alan recently shut down.
对吗
Is that correct?
我没把阿兰怎么样  我是无辜的
I didn't do anything to Alan. I'm innocent.
无辜者一般不会跟到受害者的停车场去
Innocent men don't usually stalk their victims in parking lots.
我就是想跟阿兰谈谈而已
I just wanted to talk to Alan. That's all.
我需要找到合适的时机
I needed to find the right moment.
我们得单独谈
We had to be alone.
好吧
Okay.
你想跟他谈什么
What did you want to talk to him about?
休姆先生  如果你只是想跟他谈
Mr. Hume, if all you wanted to do was talk to him,
那为什么警员找到你时
then why did UNIs find you
你带着两个箱子和一张去墨西哥的票
with two suitcases and a ticket to Mexico?
因为我不想死
Because I don't want to die.
他们找上了阿兰  那我就是下一个了
They came after Alan and I'm next.
"他们"是谁
Who's "they"?
如果你知道是谁想杀阿兰  你得告诉我们
If you know who went after Alan, you need to tell us.
是你们公司的人吗
Was it someone from your company?
你是告密者吗  格伦
Are you a whistle-blower, Glen?
你是想揭露什么吗
Is there something you're trying to expose?
你是为这个找阿兰吗
Is that why you wanted to talk to Alan?
纽约警局可以保护你
The NYPD can protect you,
如果真有人想杀你
and if someone really is trying to kill you,
你待在我们这里
you're a lot safer in here with us
比自己在外更安全
than out there, on your own.
好吧
Okay.
但不是我们公司的人
But it's not someone from my company.
是黑帮
It's the mob.
有组织犯罪跟阿兰怎么会扯上关系
What would organized crime want with Alan?
废物管理
Waste management.
对
Yeah.
他们逼我跟他们签下
They strong-armed me into giving them the contract
我公司危险废料处理的合约
for my factory's hazardous-waste disposal.
他们在城里到处这么干
They've been doing the same thing all over town.
他们直接把这些东西倾倒进垃圾堆
And they just dump the stuff into the landfill.
他们为什么会先找上阿兰
So, why would they target Alan before you?
因为阿兰解雇了戴夫·巴顿
Because Alan fired Dave Barton,
他们唯一能买通的检查员
the only inspector that they could buy.
所以阿兰成了碍事的
So Alan was becoming a big problem,
他们唯一的解决方案就是杀了他
and their only solution was to kill him.
黑帮想杀我
The mob is trying to kill me?
想  但没成功  知道为什么吗
Trying and failing. But do you know why?
因为我是  落健侠吗
Because I'm -- I'm, what, Rogaine Man?
恶心  最糟的一个名字了
Yuck. Worst name yet.
但这能解释你为什么总能起死回生
But it does explain why you keep coming back to life.
你的细胞以惊人速度重生
Your cells regenerate at an amazing rate.
但是并没有
Except they don't.
什么
What?
刚拿到了检测结果
Just got the test back.
血液和组织细胞都没有
No sign of abnormal regenerative activity
异常再生活动的迹象
in blood or tissue cells.
事实上  没有任何异常迹象
In fact, no sign of anything abnormal at all.
都说了  我就是无聊侠
Told you. I'm Boring Man.
除了针对我的刺杀
Except for the contract out on my life.
为了确认  或许我们该砍下他一根手指
Just to be sure, maybe we should cut off one of his fingers,
看能不能长回来
see if it grows back.
什么
What?
就是提个建议
Just the tip.
好了  我受够了
Okay, I'm done.
你要去哪
Where you gonna go?
回家  不回家  去个安全的地方
Home. Or not home. Somewhere safe.
哪里安全
Where is that?
我家
My place.
我们尚未解谜你异能的秘密
We have yet to unlock the secrets of your powers.
蕾妮是个医生  她可以给你仔细检查
Lanie's a doctor. She can strip you down and check you out.
-不要  -别想
- No! - Forget it!
拜托  你欠他的
Come on! You owe him!
不不  才不呢
No. No, she doesn't!
卡塞尔  今天很漫长了  我累坏了
Castle, it's been a long day. I am very overwhelmed.
我只想回到我的生活中
I just want to go back to my life.
太糟了  你不能
That's too bad. You can't.
被咬后  蜘蛛侠不能回到从前
Spidey couldn't go back after the bite.
炸弹爆炸后  绿巨人也无法回到过去
Hulk couldn't go back after the bomb.
蚁人也是...
The Ant-Man couldn't go back after --
记不起来是咋回事了
I can't remember.
重点是  你有义务
Point is, you have an obligation.
能力越大  责任就越大
With great power comes great responsibility.
我们去我家  点些披萨
Let's go to my place and get some pizza on the way.
我绝不会回你家吃披萨
There is no way I'm going back to your place to eat pizza
并探索我的超能力
and explore my superpowers.
我会告诉你格温是怎么说你的
I'll tell you what Gwen said about you.
好吧
Okay.
废料处理公司查得如何了
Where are we on the waste-management company?
是一家新公司  叫做靶眼
It's a new entity called Bullseye.
我们不清楚经营者是谁
We're not sure who's running it,
但据传是新人物
but rumor is it's a new player on the scene.
不对劲
I don't know.
触电和下毒不像黑帮的作风
Electrocution and poisoning doesn't sound like the mob.
-是啊  -除非是不想引起注意
- No. - Unless they're trying to keep a low profile.
不引起我们注意的最好办法是别张扬
The best way to stay off our radar is to fly under it.
是啊
Yeah, true.
你们去二楼
Why don't you guys head down to the second floor,
看看有组织犯罪有什么看法
see if Organized Crime has any insight?
好的
Okay.
我们知道你能扛过中毒和触电
We know you can survive poisoning and electrocution.
现在该看看你是否能扛过穿透伤了
Now it's time to see if you can survive penetrative wounds.
我们从小点的东西起步吧
How about if we start with some smaller,
比如纸割手
like a paper cut?
好吧  这有点过了
Okay, this is all a little overwhelming.
我理解  好
I understand. All right.
我们先试试其他的超能力吧
Let's -- Let's test for some other powers first.
念力
Telekinesis.
试试用你的意念移动钢琴
Try to move the piano with your mind.
如果我做了  你能告诉我格温的事吗
If I try this, will you tell me about Gwen?
好的
Deal.
搞什么
What the hell?
那是个小伎俩
That was a trick.
是想测试蜘蛛侠的灵敏感知
I was actually testing for Spidey-sense.
我没有
I don't have it!
显然的
Clearly.
我们能休息一下吗
Can we take a break, please?
好吧
Fine.
不不  我不喝酒
Ah, no, no. I don't drink.
好吧
All right.
你想知道格温说了什么吗
Do you want to know what Gwen said?
是啊  总算
Yes. Finally.
好  我告诉你
All right. I'll tell you.
说啊
Well?
我在用我的意念告诉你
I'm telling you with my mind.
你接收不到吗
You're not getting it?
好吧
Okay.
坏消息  没有传心术
Well, bad news is no telepathy.
好消息是  我觉得格温喜欢你
Good news is I think Gwen is into you.
她说她觉得你很逗
She told me she thinks you're funny.
真的吗
Really?
是幽默不是怪伽的意思吗
Funny ha-ha, not funny strange?
嗯
Yeah.
-哪种啊  -没错
- Yeah, what? - Exactly.
你要不要把两次死亡经历
So are you gonna use your double death
当做警钟  约她出来呢
as a wake-up call and finally ask her out?
如果她拒绝呢
What if she says no?
如果她答应呢
What if she says yes?
好吧  我做
Okay, I'll do it.
这就对了  阿兰
That is the spirit, Alan.
我没想到你是说马上啊
Well, I didn't think you meant right now!
阿兰  择日不如撞日
Alan, there is no time like the present.
响了
It's ringing.
这太刺激了
This is very exciting.
天呐  我要吐了
Oh, my God. I'm gonna be sick.
我不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
-做你自己  -做自己
- Just be yourself. - Be myself.
所以就像这样
So, something like,
"你好这里是市安检局
"Hi, this is Alan Masters
我是阿兰·马斯特斯
from the City Department of Safety Inspection,
-工号62475  -换别的  快换
- badge number 62475-- - New plan, new plan.
还是别做你自己了  这么说
Do not be yourself. Say this --
格温  你好
Hi, Gwen. Hello.
我是阿兰·马斯特斯
This is Alan Masters of --
对  是这样
Yes, that's right.
我好多了  谢谢  你呢
I'm much better, thanks. You?
没事  我就是打电话想问你
Oh, nothing. I was just calling to see
愿不愿意跟我一块吃晚饭
if you wanted to have dinner with me.
好的  到时候见
Okay. I'll see you there.
再见
Bye.
她说她愿意
She said yes.
干得漂亮  阿兰
Well done, Alan!
我们现在就只需要计划好这次完美约会
Now all we have to do is plan the perfect date.
我们还有多少时间
How much time do we have?
我们三十分钟后在波提切利餐厅见面
Well, we're meeting - at Botticelli's in 30 minutes?
-今晚吗  -你自己说现在就要开始的
- Tonight? - You said yourself it's time to start living.
是  但我以为要等到
Yes, I just thought it would be after we apprehended
我们逮捕要害你的凶手以后
your would-be murderer.
我懂了  我要发挥我的力量
I know. I will just embrace my powers.
也许这就是我的起源故事
Maybe this is my origin story,
而和格温共进晚餐
and my dinner with Gwen
将会是好事降临的开端
will be the beginning of something really terrific!
就是这种范儿  阿兰  我要跟你一起去
That's the spirit, Alan. And I'm going with you.
求你别去
Please don't.
谋害你性命最初的两次尝试
The first two attempts on your life
本来是想低调悄无声息
were meant to be anonymous, quiet.
他们不太可能会明目张胆地动手
It's very unlikely they'd try something in a public place.
就是
Exactly.
但他们的确两次都失手了
Well, they did fail twice.
他们可能会变本加厉
They may try to kick it up a notch.
什么意思
What are you saying?
别点开胃菜
Don't order an appetizer.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
你发现什么线索了吗
You found something.
是的
Yeah.
我查了卡莱布·布朗
I ran the partial plate
上的那辆越野车的部分车牌
from that S.U.V. Caleb Brown got into,
拿到了一个名单
generated a list of names.
猜猜看谁在上面
Guess who's on it.
布鲁克斯
Brooks.
那个拿了一袋子蜘蛛的家伙
Guy with the bag of spiders
想干掉我和卡塞尔来着
who tried to take down Castle and me.
如果是布鲁克斯在机场去接的卡莱布
If Brooks picked up Caleb at the airport,
这就把卡莱布和洛克塞特直接联系起来了
then this ties Caleb directly to LokSat.
听着  这只是个开始而已
Well, look, it's a start anyway.
开始吗  这可是照片证据
A start? It's photographic evidence.
什么的证据  他跟一个坏人上了车吗
Of what? That he got into a car with a bad guy?
卡莱布是公辩律师  他为坏人说话
Caleb's a public defender. He represents bad guys.
他用的是假名
He was using an alias.
我们可以拿着这个去找卡莱布
We can use this to go at Caleb,
让他说出洛克塞特的身份
get him to reveal LokSat's identity.
直到他告知洛克塞特我们在查他
Until he alerts LokSat that we're onto him,
我们就都没命了
and then we're all dead.
不行  我们等直到找到更确切的证据
No, we got to wait until we have something more concrete.
好吧
Fine.
卡莱布的假名  彼得·麦克加菲
Caleb's alias -- Peter McCaffery.
我会继续查下去
I'll look into and see
以这个名字进行过其他出行
what other trips he's taken under that name,
看能不能查到更明确的线索
see if it leads somewhere more definitive.
我明白这让人很丧气
Look, I know this is frustrating.
但我们一步步在靠近了
But we're getting close.
我们只需要每一步走得小心一点
We just have to tread carefully.
她在那
There she is.
她看上去很漂亮
She looks nice.
这简直大错特错  我是安全检查员
This is a huge mistake. I'm a safety inspector.
这样一点都不性感
That's not even a little sexy.
比去死还吓人
This is so much scarier than dying.
你是阿兰·马斯特斯  超级英雄
You are Alan Masters, superhero.
妞都喜欢超级英雄
Chicks dig superheroes.
我要跟她说我是超级英雄吗
Should I tell her I'm a superhero?
要是我  不会这么开场
I wouldn't open with that.
好吧
Okay.
我要去了
I'm going in.
祝我好运
Wish me luck.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你好  格温
Hi, Gwen.
你好
Hi.
-你...  -见到你真好
- Wow, you -- - Good to see you.
你看上去  你看上去真美
You look -- you look great.
谢谢你能跟我一起吃饭
Thanks for having dinner with me.
经历了这样的一天  你打电话来我很惊讶
I was surprised that you called, after the day you've had.
今天真是够了  疯了
What a day, right? Crazy.
太疯狂了  我...
Just nuts. I --
我  我  我是超级英雄
I-I-I'm a superhero.
什么
What?
没什么  我打喷嚏而已
Nothing. I sneezed.
你...你打喷嚏会说"我是超级英雄"吗
You -- You sneezed, "I'm a superhero"?
对  对  过敏了
Yeah. Allergies.
超级英雄  不好意思
Superhero! Excuse me.
莱恩
Hey, Ryan.
我们查到了靶眼废物处理公司的所有者
We I.D.'d the owner of Bullseye Waste Management.
是一个叫霍雷肖·斯贝特的家伙
He's a guy named Horatio Spate.
那就是个适合超级大反派的名字
That's a good supervillain name.
没开玩笑
This is not a joke.
斯贝特涉嫌谋害了很多人
Spate is suspected of executing over a dozen people.
我把他的照片发给你了你留意一下
I texted you his picture just to put him on your radar.
不管做什么  别出门
Whatever you do, don't leave the loft.
别出门  明白了
Don't leave the loft. Got it.
等等  那是什么声音
Wait, what's that noise?
糟糕
Crap.
-你好阿兰  -我认识你吗
- Hello, Alan. - Do I know you?
抱歉打断你浪漫的晚餐
Sorry to interrupt your romantic dinner.
小心阿兰  他就是你的死对头
Careful, Alan. He's your archnemesis.
真的吗  我还有死对头
Seriously? I have an archnemesis?
他们就是这样装扮的吗
Is that how they dress?
阿兰你真可爱  我喜欢你
Alan, you're cute and I like you,
但这有点过了
but this is all a bit much.
你说你是超级英雄  他是大反派
You say that you're a superhero, and he's a supervillain.
所以你是他的跟班吗
So does that make you his sidekick?
跟班  才不是  我是导师
Sidekick? Please. I'm the mentor.
我还是他的约会对象呢
And I'm his date.
至少刚刚是
Or at least I was.
对不起  这太诡异了
I'm sorry. This is just weird.
她以为我是个疯子了  真谢谢你
And she thinks I'm crazy. Thank you so much.
都是你的错
This is all your fault.
其实  是他的错
Actually, it's his.
阿兰  这位是霍雷肖·斯贝特
Alan, meet Horatio Spate.
他是靶眼废物处理公司的新掌门人
He's the new owner of Bullseye Waste Management.
所以  你就是想要置我于死地的人吗
So, you're the one who's trying to kill me?
不  我若要你三更死  你岂能活到五更天
Hardly. If I wanted you dead, you'd be dead already.
那你想要什么
Well, what do you want?
一项互惠安排
An arrangement.
它对我们双方都有利
One that would benefit both of us.
有人两次试图杀死你
Twice someone's tried to kill you.
而你却能安然地活到现在
And you're still with us.
你认为你能幸运多久
How long before Lady Luck abandons you?
让我猜猜
Oh, let me guess.
你可以为他提供保护
A man like you can offer protection.
何止是保护  我能保证他的性命
More than offer. I can guarantee it.
作为条件  我希望你在实施安全检查时
In return, all I ask is that you adopt a more
能睁一只眼闭一只眼
laissez-faire interpretation of your inspection policies.
这是道德考验
This is a moral test.
每个超级英雄都会被大反派逼入道德困境中
Every superhero is presented with a moral dilemma by the villain,
欲使其堕落
trying to corrupt him.
霍雷肖·斯贝特  我的回答是不
Horatio Spate, my answer is no.
他要拔枪
Gun, gun.
放轻松  哥们
Relax, boys.
这是白果
It's ginkgo.
最近刚开始吃
Just started taking it.
它的作用是
Here's what it does.
提高记忆力  强化大脑功能
It improves memory, - it sharpens brain function,
促使人们作出最正确的决定
and it helps a person make really, really good decisions.
或许你该尝试一粒
Perhaps you should try one,
然后重新作出回答
then you can rethink your answer.
保重
Careful.
外面很危险哦
Dangerous out there.
他活像是从漫画里走出来的人
It's as if he stepped off the pages of a graphic novel.
你们真该亲眼见见他的
You should have been there to see him in person.
对  他们应该亲眼见
Yes. They should have.
而不是你  也绝不是阿兰
Not you, and definitely not Alan.
我知道你心知肚明
Now, tell me how dangerous it was for you
把他带去公共场合是多么危险的事
to take him out in public, 'cause I know that you knew.
他坠入爱河了  贝克特  爱情至上
He's in love, Beckett. And I love love.
对不起  不会有下次了
And I'm sorry, and I won't do it again.
是的不会有下次了  你知道为什么吗
No, you won't, and you know why?
因为在找到霍雷肖之前
Because I've had him sent to a real safe house
他会一直待在我安排的安全房里
until we track down Horatio.
头儿  我们认为他们可能想要低调
Boss, I know we were talking about flying under the radar,
但这事一点都不像是霍雷肖的风格
but that really doesn't seem to be Horatio's style.
他是用子弹来解决问题的人
I mean, he solves problems with bullets,
而不是什么下毒  或精心计划的电击圈套
not poisons and elaborate electrocution traps.
那他为什么要担保阿兰性命
So why would he guarantee protection?
可能他知道谁是真正的凶手
Oh, maybe he knows the actual identity of our would-be killer.
阻止凶手的罪行能让他控制阿兰
And stopping the hit could benefit his waste-disposal company
进而惠及他的废物处理公司
by giving him leverage on Alan.
霍雷肖有没有什么熟人最近买了TTX
Are any of Horatio's associates recent buyers of TTX?
这能帮我们缩小想杀阿兰的嫌疑人范围
'Cause that could help us narrow down who's trying to kill Alan.
清单在这里
We've got the list right here.
等等  福龙药草公司
Wait a minute. Lucky Dragon Herbologists?
霍雷肖有个小药盒  上面有龙的标识
Horatio had a pillbox with a dragon logo on it.
就是它  一样的标识
That's it. That's the same logo.
这上面说那是中国白莲教的幌子公司
It says here that it's a front for the White Lotus Chinese Triad.
这么一家国际知名黑帮持有TTX
Okay, so how does an international gang
是如何做到不被调查的呢
get cleared to possess TTX?
福龙是一家合法经营的企业
Because Lucky Dragon is a legitimate business
而且中医里有小剂量的TTX是正常的
and there are small doses of TTX in Eastern medicine.
等等  这说不通啊
Hold up. This doesn't make sense.
有情报说
According to Intel,
白莲教把霍雷肖视为眼中钉
the Triad sees Horatio as a threat to their territory.
他们之间随时会有一场血战
They're gearing up for war.
所以霍雷肖无法保证阿兰
So, no way is Horatio guaranteeing Alan's safety
不死于白莲教之手
with the Triads.
除非
Unless...
霍雷肖说他最近开始吃白果
Horatio said he just started taking ginkgo.
有没有可能这两大集团正在协商
What if the two empires are hammering out
达成某种联盟
some kind of an alliance?
阿兰不明就里地牵扯进这个联盟
An alliance that Alan unknowingly stumbled onto
成为白莲教的瓮中之鳖
and put him right in the cross hairs of the Triad.
不过到底是什么让水火不容的黑帮
But what could bring two warring gangs together
合作了呢
to join forces?
去弄一张福龙药草公司的搜查令
Well, get a search warrant for Lucky Dragon Herbologists
来查个水落石出
and find out.
卡莱布
Uh, Caleb.
你怎么来这了
What are you doing here?
不好意思打扰你了
I hate to bother you,
但我有个客户亟须你的帮助
but I could really use your help with a client.
你能过来几分钟吗
Can I borrow you for a quick minute?
当然可以
Yeah, sure.
这个客户是谁
So, who is this client?
我想你应该对他很熟
I think you're familiar with him --
彼得·麦克加菲
Peter McCaffery.
不  没听过
No, it -- it doesn't sound familiar.
没听过  我帮你回忆一下
No? Let me fill you in.
有个十分热血的警察
So, there's this overzealous cop.
你了解这种类型的  她永不言弃
You know the type. She never knows when to give up.
她让她的技术人员
And she has her tech guy
调查了彼得·麦克加菲最近的行程
look into Peter McCaffery's recent travel.
好吧
Okay.
麦克加菲先生是个十分注重隐私的人
Yeah, well, Mr. McCaffery's a very private person,
他设置了一些让人意想不到的数字绊雷
so he set up some unexpected digital trip wires.
这对技术人员和他老板来说可不是件好事
That's bad news for the tech guy and his boss.
而这位警察仍在浑然不知地迈入绝境
And so this cop, she keeps marching toward this kill zone,
除非她回头
and unless she makes an about-face,
否则她绝不会有好下场
it is not going to end well.
我不明白
I don't get it.
你曾为和平部队服役一整期
You served a full term in the Peace Corps.
你在环保局工作过
You worked for the EPA.
你用法律武器和贪污受贿的公司作斗争
You brought legal action against corrupt corporations.
你想说什么  凯特
What's your point, Kate?
究竟发生了什么
What happened?
你曾经正义有为  为什么失去了初心
You used to make a difference. Why did you sell out?
听着
Look.
我的客户是迫不得已才为他斗不过的人效力的
My client is forced to work for a man that he cannot fight.
信我的话吧  你也斗不过的
And take my word for it. Neither can you.
我们互相帮助吧
Let's help each other out here.
我们可以扳倒洛克塞特
We can bring down LokSat.
我这是再给你一个弃恶扬善的机会
I'm giving you a second chance to make a difference.
警监  别太为难自己
Captain, just do yourself a favor, hmm?
听从我的警告吧
Heed my warning.
不  还是你听我的警告吧
No, you heed mine.
你可以考虑到明晚八点
You have until 8:00 tomorrow night.
不然怎么样呢
Then what?
不然我就揭发你
I'll expose you.
我们就一起担惊受怕
And then we'll both be looking over our shoulders,
等着洛克塞特把我们灭口
waiting for LokSat to tie up loose ends.
因为他们一旦发现你的伪装身份暴露了
Because once they find out that your cover is blown
我盯上你了
and I'm onto you,
那你和我一样得死
then you're gonna be as dead as I am.
七分钟  凯特
Seven minutes, Kate.
七分钟
Seven minutes.
身体死亡后
That's how long the brain continues to function
大脑还会运行七分钟时间
after the body dies,
神经突触慢慢熄灭之际
and as all of those synapses slowly stop firing off,
就是人们常说的走马灯  一生的经历在眼前闪过
that's when they say that our lives flash before our eyes.
等你的七分钟来临的时候
Now, when your seven minutes come,
我真心希望你的眼前不会浮现这个瞬间
I sincerely hope that you do not flash to this moment,
你有机会选择生却偏要选择死的瞬间
when you had a chance to live and you chose not to.
需要我来处理吗
Do you want me to handle that?
你今天早上紧张得要命
You're on edge this morning.
紧张  我为什么要紧张
On edge? Why would I be on edge?
是因为洛克塞特的亲信知道我们盯上他了
Because LokSat's henchman knows we're onto him
刺客随时可能破门而入吗
and assassins could come through the door at any second.
我倒想问  你为什么不紧张
I mean, why aren't you on edge?
卡莱布有很多面  但是他不会自取灭亡
well, Caleb is a lot of things, but he's not suicidal,
他只能找我们帮忙
and working with us is his only recourse.
他威胁你的性命
He threatened your life.
因为他害怕了
Because he was scared.
相信我  卡塞尔  我把他说动了
Trust me, Castle. I turned him.
我确定他今天会来
I'm positive he's gonna come in today.
我也觉得他会来
Oh, yeah, I think he's coming in, too.
反正他不来就是洛克塞特的杀人小分队来
Well, either him or LokSat's kill squads.
天啊
Geez.
科博法官拒绝签署我们对
So, Judge Kober just denied our search warrant request
福龙药草公司的搜查令申请
for The Lucky Dragon.
我们怀疑那是白莲教的幌子
A suspected Triad front.
她知道两次刺杀阿兰未遂都和他们有联系吗
Does she know that we like them for two attempts on Alan's life?
她说我们还需要合理依据
Says we still need probable cause.
我们只能另辟蹊径了
Okay, we got to go at this a different way.
如果霍雷肖和白莲教
You know, if Horatio and the Triads
真的联手的话  那一定是大事
are working together, this is something big.
各位
Guys.
我知道该怎么进去了
I know how to get in.
一定要按计划行事
Stick to the plan.
放松点  我完全能搞定
Relax. I totally got this.
欢迎光临福龙药草公司
Welcome to Lucky Dragon Herbs and Remedies.
你们想要点什么
Can I help you?
安检抽查
Surprise safety inspection.
顺便提醒您  先生  他举着证件呢
FYI, sir, he's holding out a badge
上面写着安全健康部
that says - Department of Safety and Health
他的表情很严肃
and he's got a serious look on his face.
非常严肃
Very serious look.
好吧  但是为什么两个人一起来检查
Okay. But why two inspectors?
-因为他是我带的实习生  -我是实习生
- Uh, because he is my trainee... - Trainee.
多一双眼睛盯着有好处
...and it helps to have a second set of eyes.
不是说只有一双眼睛
Not that one set of eyes
或者没有眼睛就不好
or no sets of eyes is a bad thing.
你们爱带几双眼睛都行
Bring all the eyes you would like.
我敢说你们查不出我的药
I'm sure you'll find my medicines
违反你们西方的什么规矩
violate none of your Western laws.
这事我们自有判断
We'll be the judge of that.
我觉得我应该和你们在一起
I ask we stay together
这样才能给你们答疑解惑
so I may address your inspection concerns.
当然了
Of course.
我来引开他  你溜到里屋去
I'll cause a distraction. You slip to the back room.
这些是我最名贵的草药
Here are some of my most precious herbs.
这个国家长不出来的
Impossible to grow in this country.
你是说这边的草药吗
Oh, you mean these herbs right here?
你的助手笨手笨脚
Your assistant's very clumsy.
是啊  他就这样
Yes, he is.
所以我们越早查完走人越好
Which is why the sooner we get out of your way, the better.
麻烦带我们去里屋看看
Take us to your back room now, please.
那是当然
But of course.
等等  我感受到一股力量
Wait. I sense something.
一股强大的力量
Something powerful.
这是超越自然规律的存在
An unnatural presence in the order of things.
哪种存在
What kind of presence?
到底是哪种存在呢
What kind, indeed?
当凡人不再是凡人
When is a man not a man?
当生命之力无法断绝
When his life-force cannot be extinguished,
当他拥有不死之身的时候
when he cannot die.
那他就是神
Then he is a god.
我觉得他感受到你的力量了
I think he senses your powers.
真的吗  你这么觉得吗
Yeah? You do?
要不然就是他在拖延时间
Either that or he's buying time
让他的同伙把违禁品从后门运出去
while his guys get the contraband out the back door.
你们把箱子放下
You guys drop the cases.
纽约警局  跪下  伙计们
NYPD. On your knees, fellas.
这到底是什么
What the hell is this?
海洛因
Heroin.
什么时候开始海洛因长这样了
Since when does heroin look like that?
从进化成合成海洛因开始
Since it's synthetic heroin,
这是一种批量生产模拟海洛因毒瘾的类鸦片
an opioid manufactured to replicate a heroin high.
实际上  这东西是升级版
In fact, this stuff actually improves on it
因为根据我的测试分析
because, according to the analysis I ran,
它掺了河鲀毒素
it's laced with TTX.
就是那种差点杀了我的毒药
The same poison that almost killed me?
怎么  海洛因还不够危险吗
What, heroin isn't dangerous enough?
因为这宗毒药能够戒断神经元突触
Because that poison works by blocking synapses.
小剂量下  它是有效的止痛剂
In small doses, it's a powerful analgesic
尤其是消除吸食海洛因的疼痛
specifically used for the pain of heroin withdrawal.
所以它通过减轻疼痛副作用
So it makes the drug more addictive
让毒品更容易使人上瘾
by reducing the painful side effects.
就此  海洛因
So more addictive heroin
不再需要通过走私
that doesn't have to be smuggled into the country because --
因为它在美国就能制造
Because it can be made right here in the good old U.S. Of A.
这也解释了白莲教和霍雷肖
That explains why the Triads and Horatio
为什么愿意搁置争议
are willing to put their difference aside,
因为合成海洛因能值几十亿
because synthetic heroin could be worth billions.
合成海洛因能值几十亿
Synthetic heroin could be worth billions.
这和我有什么关系
What does this have to do with me?
为什么有人想要我死
Why would anybody want me dead?
显然  这东西是在某个实验室里制作的
Well, clearly this stuff is made in a lab somewhere,
而你的工作室检查实验室  所以
and your job is to inspect laboratories, so --
你知道  这种黄色看上去很眼熟
You know, this shade of yellow looks very familiar.
它怎么会是这种颜色
What is it that gives it this color?
叫做L.A.H的无机催化剂
An inorganic catalyst commonly referred to as L.A.H.
氢化锂铝
Lithium aluminum hydride?
我在检查赞提姆实验室时
That is the same chemical that spilled
泄露的就是这种化学物质
when I was inspecting Zantium Labs.
所以他们想要你死
This is why they wanted you dead.
当合成海洛因上市的时候
When the synthetic heroin hits the streets,
大家都会知道它通过L.A.H合成
it'll come out that it was made with L.A.H.
而既然你知道哪个实验室买了大量的L.A.H
And since you knew the lab had purchased large amounts of L.A.H.
他们不敢冒着
They couldn't take the risk
我可能在新闻上看见什么
that I might see something on the news,
把线索拼凑在一起
put the pieces together,
-向政府举报的风险  -意味着
- and report it to the authorities. - Which means...
赞提姆实验室的人想要杀我
Someone at Zantium Labs is trying to kill me!
赞提姆实验室的人想要杀你
...someone at Zantium Labs is trying to kill you!
天啊  我们说话听起来也是这样的吗
Oh, my God. Is that what we sound like?
希望不是
Certainly hope not.
这很可爱  但有点太可爱了
I mean, it was cute but just overly cute.
阿兰
Alan.
你知道赞提姆实验室是谁订购了L.A.H吗
Do you know who ordered the L.A.H. For Zantium?
我知道  麦克·林  首席化学家
I do. Mike Lin, the lead chemist.
我记得在订购单上看到了他的名字
I remember seeing his name on the purchase order.
也许他就是想要杀我的人
He's probably the guy who's trying to kill me.
他可能非常危险
He could be very dangerous.
我们得在他伤害别人之前
We need to get down there and figure something out
想办法搞定他
before he hurts someone else.
不  我们得很谨慎
No. We have to be very smart about this.
麦克这样的化学家
There is no way that Mike, a chemist,
不可能是他一个人行动
would be working alone here,
所以我们得先得到扣押整个实验室的法院指令
so we have to get a court order to impound the entire laboratory
确保每人毁坏任何证物
and make sure that nobody destroys any of the evidence.
需要花多久时间
Well, how long will that take?
别担心  我们会抓到他的
Don't worry. We'll get this guy.
卡塞尔  你在这啊
Oh, Castle. There you are.
我们拿到搜查令了  走吧
We got the warrant. Let's go.
好  阿兰在哪
Yeah. Where's Alan?
我以为他跟你们在一起
I thought he was with you guys.
哦  不
Oh, no.
格温
Gwen!
阿兰  你在这干什么
Alan. What are you doing here?
如果你想活命的话就跟我来
Come with me if you want to live.
阿兰  发生什么了
Alan, what is going on?
麦克·林在实验室里秘密的制作合成海洛因
Mike Lin is secretly making synthetic heroin in the lab.
就是他想要杀我
He's the one who's trying to kill me.
天啊  阿兰  你确定吗
Oh, my God. Alan, are you sure?
是啊  但别担心
Yeah. But don't worry.
警察马上就过来
The cops are on the way,
在那之前  我会保护你
and until then, I'll protect you.
这个能用
This'll work.
如果那个老瞎子能用  我也能用
Yeah, if that old blind guy could use it, so could I.
或者  那个其实更好
Or -- Or that's actually better.
等等  你为什么有枪
Wait. Why do you have a gun?
-我要杀了麦克  -不
- I'm gonna kill Mike. - No.
不  不  警察会逮捕他的
No, no, no. The cops will arrest him.
这就是我害怕的
That's what I'm afraid of.
麦克是这唯一
Mike is the only person here
知道我在掌控毒品生意的人
who knows that I'm running this drug operation.
什么
What?
等等  是你给我下毒的
Wait, you're the one who poisoned me?
还有要电死你  是的
And electrocuted you, yeah.
我在试图保持低调
I was trying to be discreet.
我男朋友霍雷肖说
I mean, my boyfriend Horatio
我应该直接朝你脑袋上开一枪  但
said I should just shoot you in the head, but --
等等  别说了
Hold on! Stop everything!
哇
Wha--
霍雷肖是你男朋友
Horatio is your boyfriend?
所以  我猜第二次约会是没戏了
So I guess a second date is out of the question?
阿兰
Alan.
你真的觉得像你这样的人跟我有戏吗
You seriously thought a guy like you had a shot with me?
我还认为濒死两次很痛苦
I thought dying twice was painful.
也许第三次不会有这么难受了
Well, maybe it won't be so bad the third time.
-警察  -都别动  纽约警察
- Police! - Nobody move! NYPD!
马上  举起手来
Right now! Put up your hands!
-举起手来  -把你的手放在我们视线内
- Get 'em up! - Get your hands where we can see 'em!
手  手
Hands. Hands.
看到阿兰了吗
Any sign of Alan?
不  还没有
No, not yet.
我确定他到这来了
I'm sure he came here.
看看你能找到格温的办公室吗
See if you can find Gwen's office.
阿兰
Alan!
哦  不
Oh, no.
这是我的错误
This is my fault.
我在他身上强加了超级英雄的责任
I forced the superhero mantle onto him.
我向他灌输了他是刀枪不入的这种疯狂的念头
I filled his head with crazy ideas of being invulnerable,
然后就像伊卡洛斯一样
and then, like some superhero Icarus,
他飞得离太阳太近了
he flew too close to the sun.
阿兰  对不起  我很抱歉
Alan, I'm sorry. I am so sorry.
我让你失望了
I let you down!
谢谢
Thank you.
没关系
Don't mention it.
阿兰  你还活着
Alan! You're alive?
别这么大声
Shh! Not so loud.
我头疼的快炸了似的
I've got a splitting headache.
我来  叫辆救护车吧
I'll, uh, call an ambulance?
放轻松  我没事
Relax. I'm fine.
我只需要吃两片止痛片
I just need a couple of Advil.
-怎么  出什么事了  卡塞尔  -你
- What? What is it, Castle? - You --
我脑袋上是不是被开了一枪
Did I get shot in the head?
正中间  我是说  你怎么可能
Right in the middle! I mean, how did you even --
等一下  这说明你看到杀你的人了
Wait, that means you've seen your killer.
谁  是谁
Who -- Who was it?
你肯定猜不到
You're never gonna guess.
我在她准备给药剂师麦克来一枪的时候抓住了她
I took her down just before she put a bullet in Mike the chemist.
该死的你为什么就是不肯死
Why the hell won't you die?
我一直都不觉得她适合你
I never thought she was right for you.
我见过的最酷的事情
Coolest thing ever.
如你所见  子弹射进却没有穿透
As you can see, the slug pierced but didn't penetrate
阿兰头骨的垂直板
the vertical plate of Alan's skull.
真的吗  我知道那只是个点22口径的左轮手枪
Really? I realize it was only a .22-caliber revolver,
但那可是近距离射击
but it was fired at point-blank range.
你听起来对我还活着有点失望
Hey, you sound a little upset that I'm still alive.
不  我只是  好啦
No. It's just -- Oh, come on.
我想这次你应该无法解释了
I don't suppose you have an explanation this time.
介于他在过去的48小时里已经死了三次
Well, considering he's already died three times in 48 hours,
这还重要吗
does it even matter?
终于体会我的心情了吧
Welcome to the club.
阿兰  从专业医学角度出发
Alan, it's my professional medical opinion
你是我见过的最幸运的
that you're the luckiest man who's ever lived
死而复生的人
and kept living even after he died.
谢了  医生
Thanks, Doc.
你感觉如何
How you feeling?
要知道  我很感激
You know, I'm grateful.
尤其是我新交到的朋友
Especially for the new friend I made.
我非常希望我们可以保持联系
I sure hope we could stay in touch.
你在开玩笑吗  你和我
Are you kidding? You and me?
这会是一个美丽的开始
This is the start of a beautiful --
我不觉得他是在和你说话
I don't think he's talking to you.
也许你有一些我们没见过的特殊能力
Hey, maybe you have a few secret powers we haven't seen yet.
就像我一直说的那样
Which is what I've been saying all along.
但是也许这些能力的发现
But perhaps discovery of those abilities
最好交给一个医学专家
is best left to a medical expert.
回见  卡塞尔
Buh-bye, Castle.
慢走不送
Get to stepping.
好  谢谢
Okay, yeah, thanks.
是维克拉姆
That was Vikram.
缉毒组逮捕了霍雷肖和白莲教的几个成员
The DEA just arrested Horatio and a few members of the Triad.
所以有什么不对
So, what's wrong?
和卡莱布约定的期限已经过了
Caleb's deadline has come and gone
维克拉姆说他失踪了
and Vikram's said that he's disappeared.
他潜逃了
He gone off-grid.
他在逃命
He's running.
不敢面对洛克塞特  不敢和我们合作
Too scared to face LokSat, too scared to work with us.
这意味着我们失去了唯一的线索
Which means we just lost our only lead.
所以我们要怎么做
So, what do we do?
我不知道  也许你是对的
I don't know. Maybe you're right.
也许是时候有所改变了
Maybe it is time for a change.
我听说这个时候的巴黎很不错
I hear Paris is nice this time of year.
只要和你在一起  我去哪都好
So long as I'm with you, I'll go anywhere.
别  别开枪
Oh, don't -- don't shoot me.
我会把我的苏格兰威士忌洒了的
I might spill my Scotch.
我想你说的是我的苏格兰威士忌
I think you mean my Scotch.
而且是我最贵的苏格兰威士忌
And my most expensive Scotch.
物有所值
It's worth it.
你改变主意了  卡莱布
You had a change of heart, Caleb?
要知道  每天早晨我们醒来
You know, every morning we wake up
然后选择我们要做谁
and we choose who we want to be.
我醒来然后问自己  为什么我这样选择
I wake up and I ask myself, "Why are you choosing this?"
因为你说的对  凯特  我曾经是个好人
Because you're right, Kate. I was a good guy once.
你仍然可以是
And you still can be.
谁是洛克赛特
Who is LokSat?
我不知道
I don't know.
算了吧  你为他效力
Oh, come on. You work for him.
是  但我最开始是为他的同伙工作
Yes. But I started out working for his partner.
威廉·布莱肯议员
Senator William Bracken?
所以  怎么  洛克赛特把你接过去了
So, what, LokSat inherited you?
更像是招募
It was more like drafted.
布莱肯被杀之后
After Bracken's murder,
我在我的门阶上收到了这个和一张便笺
I received this on my doorstep with a note.
上面写着"布朗先生  现在开始你为我工作"
And I quote, "Mr. Brown, you now work for me.
这个手机是用卫星定位启动的
This cellphone is enabled with GPS and will only function
只有在艾斯特公园最北边才能用
at the northernmost end of Astor Park.
每月第三个周一早晨八点到那里
Be there every third Monday of the month at 8:00 a.m.
接受指令
to receive your orders.
凯特  这是你的了
Kate, it's yours.
希望下次通话你可以追踪到洛克赛特
And hopefully you can trace LokSat's next call.
他们会知道我不是你
They're gonna know I'm not you.
我们没有对话  电话响  我接
We don't have a conversation. The phone rings, I answer.
一个电脑处理过的声音告诉我指令
An electronically modified voice gives me instructions.
整个过程持续不到60秒
It lasts no more than 60 seconds,
所以让你最得力的手下做好准备
so have your best people ready.
你去哪里
Where are you going?
我会去以前去的地方  办公室  家
I'm gonna go to the same places that I always go -- work, home.
我会装作一切照旧
I'm gonna act as if nothing has changed.
但是一切已经变了  我们可以保护你
Yeah, but it has. And we can protect you.
我想从你这里得到的只有你的承诺
All I want from you is your promise
承诺你会坚持到底
that you will see this thing through.
记得我今天的选择
And remember who I chose to be today
因为没有其他人会这样做
because nobody else will.
那个苏格兰威士忌真是太好喝了  里克
That's a damn fine Scotch, Rick.
就是它了
This is it.
-这是我们接近洛克赛特的唯一机会  -是的
- It's our one shot at LokSat. - Yeah.
等时机到来之时  我们要把握住
And when the time comes, we're gonna make it count.